# Gaurav Kumar

gauravk410@gmail.com | 9871670337

# **SUMMARY**

SENIOR FRONT-END DEV WITH 5.4 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE IN BUILDING WEB APPLICATIONS USING REACTJS AND MODERN JS TOOLS/FRAMEWORKS.
COLLABORATED WITH MULTIPLE PRODUCT TEAMS TO EXECUTE NEW FEATURES. HAVE GOOD TECHNICAL SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE OF BACK-END TECHNOLOGY AS WELL.

### LINKS

GitHub:// gauravkumar386 HackerRank:// gauravk410 LinkedIn:// gauravkumar

### SKILLS

### **PROGRAMMING**

ReactJS • Redux • NextJS • Javascript • TypeScript
React Native • HTML/SCSS
Bootstrap • Java Spring Boot
Angular 2+ • DS & Algorithms

#### Tools

GIT • Azure Devops • JIRA • MySQL

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### SPOT ON AWARD

 Received this award for my exemplary dedication and work towards delivering the application

#### **TEAM APPRECIATION**

 Got appreciation for achieving release within deadline with no bugs given

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SAPIENS** | SENIOR FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Dec 2023 - Present | Bengaluru, India

# South Carolina Workers' Compensation (Dec 23 - Present) - NextJS, React, Javascript

- Worked on Keycloak tool to add extra layer of security(MFA and 2 step verification) for Login/SignUp and forgot password feature.
- Worked on policy details page to display different policies inside a table with pagination, sorting and filter.
- Implemented Premium Audit feature to verify and assess the accuracy of the premiums paid by businesses.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define data requirements and ensure seamless integration of API services.

#### **ACCENTURE** | FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Dec 2021 - Dec 2023 | Bengaluru, India

# BRISTOL MYERS SQUIBB (MAR 23 - DEC 23) - REACTJS, REDUX, JAVASCRIPT, HTML/SCSS

- Implemented advanced search feature to find list based on multiple selected combinations.
- Implemented text selector feature to higlight selected paragraphs from different section for comparison and export same data to downloadable file.

#### WALGREENS (DEC 22 - MAR 23) - REACTJS, JAVASCRIPT, HTML/SCSS

- Prepared multiple OSI Group data table pages for 5000 records using react-data-grid with filter and sorting functionality
- Implemented excel file upload to populate data into table and export functionality to download same

# <u>National Cultural Hub</u> (Jun 22 - Nov 22) - ReactJS, Redux, Javascript, Bootstrap

- Implemented User Registration functionality to pre populate fields from api response with validation & error messages
- Implemented feature to create list of carousel cards which navigates to its details page using route data id
- Implemented multi stepper form having blog creation using react-draft-wysiwyg and cover image upload to show in blog

# METROLINX (DEC 21 - MAY 22) - REACTJS, REDUX, JAVASCRIPT, HTML/SCSS

- Implemented Anonymous Login/Logout feature for Metrolinx presto
- Implemented Card Activation, blocking card, transfer card to another, deactivating card features using multi-form Stepper and Formik
- Worked with Redux and integration of api calls to sync and populate form data

## **EDUCATION**

#### **KIIT UNIVERSITY**

B.TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE June 2019 | Bhubaneshwar, Odisha GPA: 7.3 / 10.0

#### S M ARYA PUBLIC SCHOOL

10+2 SENIOR SECONDARY HIGH SCHOOL

May 2014 | New Delhi, India Percentage: 75%

#### MINDTREE LIMITED | JAVA FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Jun 2019 - Nov 2021 | Bengaluru, India

# <u>Jumeirah</u> (Oct 19 - Nov 21) - ReactJS, Redux, Javascript, HTML/SCSS

- Implemented Back Button feature on each page for navigating & retention of page data with Redux
- Implemented booking flow having Rate selection pages and Checkout details page having overview of booking details
- Created point based booking flow and implemented hidden promo code as part of booking flow to show different rates to user based on hotels
- Created payment, order & payment history page and integrated payment page with third party for EMENU web app of Jumeirah
- Created offer page having list of offers carousels with infinite scroll where user can filter offers based on hotels
- Created responsive pages using HTML/SCSS and written unit test cases

#### SITA (Jun 19 - Oct 19) - Java Spring Boot, Angular 6

- Worked on creation of apis using spring boot for generating billing & taxation reports for SITA QTB & Non-QTB products
- Developed billing form page for customer using Angular 6
- Created list of products in UI having sorting & searching functionality and api to integrate data and downloading the file
- Created apis to upload text file for testing set of data in UI
- Written Junit test cases to increase code coverage by 30%